whatruns.com 2019-05-03

# Privacy Policy — WhatRuns

Thanks for visiting whatruns.com.

This privacy policy explains the what, how, and why of the personally identifying Information we collect when you visit the website located at www.whatruns.com (the “Site”) and when you use the WhatRuns extensions and services (“Services”) and includes Personal Information collected via email, SMS, telephone, WAP or other means. It also explains the specific ways we use and disclose that information. By using or accessing the Site or Services, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy, and you are consenting to our processing of your information as described below.

### Information we collect

#### Browse Extensions

No visitor information is ever logged. Period.

Browsers may show a warning sign because the WhatRuns extension reads some code snippets from the websites you visit. It allows the extension to reveal technologies used on websites you visit.

#### Website

If you are a Visitor, WhatRuns collects information on your use of our Site, such as pages visited, links clicked, non-sensitive text entered, and mouse movements, as well as information more commonly collected such as the referring URL, browser, operating system, cookie information, and Internet Service Provider (“Usage Data”). WhatRuns’s purpose in collecting Usage Information is to better understand how WhatRuns’s Visitors use the Site. WhatRuns does not use the Usage Information to identify its Visitors and does not disclose the Usage Information other than under the circumstances described in this Privacy Policy.

As a Visitor, WhatRuns collects potentially personally identifying information like Internet Protocol (or “IP”) addresses (“Potential PII”). Also, you may choose to interact with the Site that results in your providing Personal Information to WhatRuns, such as giving us your name, email address, user name and password when signing up for a free trial of the Services or creating an account to post comments to the WhatRuns blog or social media sites, etc. You should be aware that any information you provide in the WhatRuns blog or social media areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.

We only collect Personal Information that is reasonable or necessary to accomplish the purpose of your interaction with WhatRuns as a Visitor. You may choose not to provide this information but you need to understand that as a result, you may not be able to engage in certain activities on the Site. Any Personal Information provided by you as a Visitor to the Site will be used only as described in this Privacy Policy and WhatRuns’s Acceptable Use Policy located at our website.

If you are a Customer of WhatRuns, when you signed up for the Services, you entered into an agreement with WhatRuns to accept WhatRuns’s terms of use of the Services, which includes the obligations in this Privacy Policy and our Acceptable Use Policy (“Agreement”). As part of your use of the Services, we collect the same information as that of a Visitor above and may ask you for additional information such as payment information, usage data in relation to the Services and other information we deem relevant for the purpose of providing the Services.

WhatRuns may use your information and data as agreed to in the Agreement and to:

  * Process transactions between you and WhatRuns.
  * Send e-mails about our Site or respond to inquiries.
  * Send e-mails and updates about the WhatRuns Services, including newsletters.
  * Provide support for the WhatRuns Services.
  * Enhance or improve user experience, our Site, or WhatRuns Services.
  * Monitor data to ensure that it complies with your contractual obligations to us.
  * Perform any other function that we believe in good faith is necessary to protect the security or proper functioning of our Site or the WhatRuns Services.
  * With your prior consent, we may post your personal testimonials along with those of other satisfied customers on our Site in addition to other endorsements.

The information we collect from a Customer is disclosed only in accordance with the Agreement and this Privacy Policy and the Acceptable Use Policy.

#### Right to Access, Edit, and Remove Your Information

You have a right to access personal information we hold about you. Whenever you use our Site or WhatRuns Services, we strive to make sure that the Personal Information is correct. If that information is wrong, we give you ways to update it quickly or to delete it – unless we have to keep that information for legitimate business or legal purposes. When updating your Personal Information, we may ask you to verify your identity before making any changes. We may reject requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort (for example, developing a new system or fundamentally changing an existing practice), risk the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup systems). Where we can provide information access and correction, we will do so for free, except where it would require a disproportionate effort. Because we protect information from accidental or malicious destruction, even after information is deleted from the WhatRuns Services, it may not be immediately deleted from WhatRuns’s servers. To request removal of your Personal Information from our Site, Services, blog or social media, contact us at hello [at] whatruns.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

If a User interacts with one of our Customers and the User seeks to access, or correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data or no longer wants to be contacted by one of our Customers, the User should direct its inquiry to the Customer because the Customer is the data controller. If the Customer requests WhatRuns to remove the Personal Information, we will respond to their request within 30 days.

#### Disclaimer Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer to help the website analyse how visitors use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

### Security Measures

We take measures to enhance the security of our Site and the WhatRuns Service. These measures include using SSL Certificates and two-factor authentication. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. No security measures are perfect and we cannot promise that the information about you will remain secure in all circumstances.

### Do Not Track Signal

We treat the data of everyone who comes to our site in accordance with this Privacy Policy, whatever their Do Not Track setting.

### Children

Our site is intended for a general audience and we do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 13.

### How WhatRuns Collects Information?

Cookies are small data files placed on your computer by the websites you visit and the emails you read and can be used to help recognize you when you return to a website, or when you visit other sites. We, or third party service providers, may use cookies to, among other things, measure activity, personalize your experience, remember your viewing preferences, or track your status or progress when accessing our site. For some of these purposes, our cookies may be tied to Personal Information and/or Potential PII. In particular, the WhatRuns Services use first-party cookies to maintain a coherent scope for a user session across multiple pages on a single website. These cookies do not track the same user across unrelated domains and, as described above, attempts to infer identity across domains is strictly prohibited.

Local Storage is a standard facility provided by HTML5-compliant browsers used to retain data on your computer across visits to the same website. We use local storage as a temporary holding area for user events that were observed locally but, due to the timing of a page unload, were unable to be transmitted as part of the user session. Return visits to the same website read and transmit events previously stored in local storage to complete previously recorded sessions.

This information may in the aggregate identify a User, however we will not identify a User as they browse the web if the User turns off cookies, as explained below.

WhatRuns does not and will not ever attempt to identify the same person across disparate, unrelated domains. It is a violation of our Acceptable Use Policy for our customers to attempt to build multi-site user profiles for the intent of selling or exchanging lists of users or demographic information.

### Opting Out

If you wish to prevent all websites using the WhatRuns Services to be able to record an its activity, you can opt-out of the WhatRuns Services. Opting out will create a cookie that tells WhatRuns to turn off recording on any site which uses the WhatRuns Services. The presence of this cookie is required to continue opting out, so if you clear your browser cookies, you will have to opt-out again. (We regret that there isn't a better way to make your opt-out more permanent, but due to technical reasons, this really is the best we can do at present.)

### Blocking Cookies

If you choose, you can set your browser to reject cookies or you can manually delete individual or all of the cookies on your computer by following your browser’s help file directions. Note that turning off cookies may also disable functions of many websites you visit. If your browser is set to reject cookies or you manually delete cookies, WhatRuns will not be able to coalesce your anonymous user identity automatically into sessions across pages on the same website.

### EU Privacy Shield Framework

WhatRuns complies with the EU Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the EU regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. WhatRuns has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles will govern.

### Changes

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. When there are changes to this Privacy Policy, we will update this page. The date on the bottom will always indicate when we last made changes. If you are a visitor to this Site and disagree with the Privacy Policy, you should leave the Site and/or cancel your agreement with WhatRuns.

### What If I Have Questions or Concerns?

If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy when using WhatRuns, please send us a detailed message to hello [at] whatruns.com
